# **Abdul Latif**

## Developer

Address Kochi, India 683105

Phone +916235731116

E-mail abdullikes@gmail.com

**LinkedIn** http://www.linkedin.com/in/abdul-latif-814418124

Technology Analyst with more than 5 years of experience in Network processes, Software
development with experience in programming languages like C, C++, JAVA, Python and MEA(R)N.
 Possess good knowledge of MEA(R)N Stack – Full stack Web development and Django. Developed
test tools to automate manual data error checking thus enhanced accuracy by 45%.

#### **Technical Profile**

- MEA(R)N Stack Full stack Web Development - Angular & React
- C
- C++
- OpenGL
- Visual Basic
- Python

- HTML
- Selenium
- Django
- Java
- Microsoft Office
- MySQL

# **Work History**

08-2023 - Present

#### Intern

Luminar Technolab Pvt Ltd, Cochin

#### 01-2023 - 07-2023

## **Technology Analyst**

Infosys, Thiruvananthapuram

- Resolved technical issues promptly for clients to minimize data network implementation downtime by 20%.
- Streamlined and rectified more complex field network design issues; achieved a 25% increase in customer issue resolution rate.
- Launched a comprehensive system training and coached 3 new joiners, enabling personnel to stay abreast of the latest practices and procedures, resulting in a remarkable 30% improvement in team performance.
- Reduced customer downtime by 30% with functional approach to incident resolution.

#### 07-2021 - 12-2022

## **Testing Associate**

Infosys, Thiruvananthapuram

- Identified, categorized, prioritized and solved 3000+ customer-facing incidents in field networks; reduced customer downtime by 30%.
- Fixed 500+ incidents in client field network designs and achieved 75% reduction in execution time.

• Collaborated with QA team to Review, analyze, recognize and report issues and reported 3 critical Network design incompatibility issues prior to installation, preventing potential customer dissatisfaction.

#### 01-2020 - 06-2021 Senior Testing Executive

Infosys, Thiruvananthapuram

- Developed an error capturing and reporting Tool in Python that automatically analyzed network design limits, region premises, and cable length constraints and inconsistencies in QA team suggested designs to enhance design accuracy by 45% and enhanced quality checks.
- Designed and placed network architecture designs for an MNC, resulting in a 30% reduction in latency and a 20% increase in overall customer satisfaction.
- Generated and proposed innovative designs for quality equipment and cable placement, resulting in a 25% reduction in installation time and a 15% increase in overall network performance.

#### 10-2018 - 12-2019 **Testing Executive**

Infosys, Thiruvananthapuram

- Engineered and executed an automated data checking tool using Python, reducing manual data verification time by 75% and minimizing errors by 90%.
- Conducted comprehensive network quality checks, identifying and resolving 50+ issues per week, resulting in a 25% decrease in customer complaints and improved overall network reliability.

#### **Education**

#### 06-2018 - 09-2018 Testing Executive Trainee: Computer Science

Infosys Global Education Centre - Mysuru, India

# 06-2015 – 05-2018 Bachelor of Computer Applications: Computer Science

MES College, Aluva - Kerala, India

• Secured CGPA of 7.65 (76.5% marks).

# **Accomplishments**

- Secured the top position in the C test competition held by the renowned and prestigious Indian Institute of Technology, Bombay.
- Showcased technical prowess by developing the visually stunning 2-D video game 'Sky Diver" for an Exhibition "Marian Expo," utilizing C++, SDL graphics library, and IrrKlang sound library; received accolades for engaging gameplay and creative design.

## Languages